{
    "id": "de3d4efe3b5347baa56fdbfe69db0652",
    "title": "Though, although, even if, even though, in spite of, or despite?",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "5163b761b6214c0f8473ba4e66335e1e",
            "title": "Though, although, even though, even if, in spite of or despite",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "I enjoyed the party ................................. having a headache.",
                    "description": "Both despite and in spite of are possible here. They are both prepositions and can be followed by a noun or an -ing form. Though and although are conjunctions and should be followed by clauses.",
                    "answers": [
                        "despite",
                        "though",
                        "although",
                        "in spite of"
                    ],
                    "correct": 3
                },
                {
                    "question": ".......................... he was there, he did not acknowledge my presence.",
                    "description": "Though and although are conjunctions and should be followed by clauses. In spite of and despite are prepositions.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Either though or although",
                        "Despite",
                        "In spite",
                        "Despite or in spite of"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "......................... she was angry, she said nothing.",
                    "description": "Though and although are conjunctions and need to be followed by clauses.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Either though or although",
                        "Either in spite of or despite",
                        "In spite of"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "She passed her exam ............................ having a bad teacher.",
                    "description": "Despite is a preposition and can be followed by a noun or -ing form. In spite is not a preposition. The correct expression is in spite of.",
                    "answers": [
                        "despite of",
                        "in spite",
                        "despite"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "......................... the train was late, I managed to arrive on time.",
                    "description": "Even though refers to the past even if refers to the future.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Despite",
                        "Even though",
                        "Even if"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "I will do it ........................... it kills me.",
                    "description": "Even if refers to the future. Even though refers to the past. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "even though",
                        "though",
                        "even if"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "............................. his disability, he works very hard.",
                    "description": "The expressions though, although, even though and even if are all conjunctions and should be followed by a clause. In spite of is a preposition. It is followed by a noun or ing form.",
                    "answers": [
                        "In spite of",
                        "Although",
                        "Even though"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": ".................................... I didn't understand a word, I kept smiling.",
                    "description": "Though and even though have similar meanings. Even though is more emphatic. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "Though",
                        "Even though",
                        "Either though or even though"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "The strongest argument, ............................., is political not economic.",
                    "description": "Though can be used as an adverb and it means 'however'. Even though and although cannot be used with this meaning. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "even though",
                        "although",
                        "though"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "............................ I don't agree with his views, I think he is honest.",
                    "description": "Though, although and even though have the same meaning. Even though is more emphatic than though or although.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Though",
                        "Although",
                        "Even though",
                        "All of the above"
                    ],
                    "correct": 3
                },
                {
                    "question": ".............................. she worked very hard, she didn't get the promotion.",
                    "description": "Despite is a preposition and cannot be followed by a clause. Even if refers to the future. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "Despite",
                        "Though",
                        "Even if"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "............................... of performing well in the interview, she didn't get the job.",
                    "description": "Even if and even though are conjunctions followed by clauses.",
                    "answers": [
                        "In spite of",
                        "Even if",
                        "Even though"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}